<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lishan AZ</title>
    <link>http://lishanaz.com/lishanaz/public/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Lishan AZ</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 00:15:59 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://lishanaz.com/lishanaz/public/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Locker</title>
      <link>http://lishanaz.com/lishanaz/public/the-locker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://lishanaz.com/lishanaz/public/the-locker/</guid>
      <description>The Locker is a mixed-reality installation game in which you explore physical artifacts with your hands and reveal memories using a bewitched magnifying glass.
You receive a note from Jade, a student at your high school who has recently gone missing, and decide to do some snooping. Inside her locker, you find diary entries to read, physical puzzles to solve, artifacts to investigate, and memories to reveal with your magnifying glass.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Residue</title>
      <link>http://lishanaz.com/lishanaz/public/residue/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://lishanaz.com/lishanaz/public/residue/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On the Safe Side</title>
      <link>http://lishanaz.com/lishanaz/public/safe-side/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://lishanaz.com/lishanaz/public/safe-side/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shonnie&#39;s Daycare Quest</title>
      <link>http://lishanaz.com/lishanaz/public/shonnie-daycare/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://lishanaz.com/lishanaz/public/shonnie-daycare/</guid>
      <description>Shonnie&amp;rsquo;s Daycare Quest is an interactive animated film about a mother trying to obtain subsidized childcare for her daughter in Washington, DC. The player makes decisions for Shonnie as she jumps through bureaucratic hoops, trying to succeed before Shonnie gets fired for missing too many days of work. This story is based on the testimony of real women in Washington, DC, archived through the advocacy work of Empower DC and Grassroots DC.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bernie &#43; Bernice</title>
      <link>http://lishanaz.com/lishanaz/public/bernie-bernice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://lishanaz.com/lishanaz/public/bernie-bernice/</guid>
      <description>Bernie + Bernice is a 1- or 2-person interactive experience that is intended for lobbies and other passive public spaces. During gameplay, players move their bodies to control a particle system displayed on a large screen in front of them. Particles leave a trace of their recent movement, allowing players to create ephemeral particle art as they move. One player alone can control the system to satisfaction, but a second player introduces a new strong force that allows them to manipulate the system together.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bathroom Experiment</title>
      <link>http://lishanaz.com/lishanaz/public/bathroom-experiment/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://lishanaz.com/lishanaz/public/bathroom-experiment/</guid>
      <description>The Bathroom Experiment was an interactive intervention performed in USC&amp;rsquo;s School of Cinematic Arts (SCA). We performed the experiment in 14 men&amp;rsquo;s and women&amp;rsquo;s bathrooms (12 in SCA, 2 in a dining hall) by writing a question in dry-erase marker on the bathroom mirror, and leaving a marker tethered to the sink for future bathroom visitors to use. We deliberately chose the private space of bathrooms to stage this public conversation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Downtown Browns</title>
      <link>http://lishanaz.com/lishanaz/public/downtown-browns/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://lishanaz.com/lishanaz/public/downtown-browns/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ascension</title>
      <link>http://lishanaz.com/lishanaz/public/ascension/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://lishanaz.com/lishanaz/public/ascension/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Light Snatcher</title>
      <link>http://lishanaz.com/lishanaz/public/light-snatcher/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://lishanaz.com/lishanaz/public/light-snatcher/</guid>
      <description>Light Snatcher is a fast-paced collaborative game played on a strip of LED lights with mobile controllers. Each player (up to 6) is assigned a color and controls a small section of the strip. When the light moves through your section, tap your phone to &amp;ldquo;snatch&amp;rdquo; it. Each time the light is captured, it speeds up, making it harder to catch.
Light Snatcher is played on a flexible, water-proof strip of lights.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Commute</title>
      <link>http://lishanaz.com/lishanaz/public/commute/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://lishanaz.com/lishanaz/public/commute/</guid>
      <description>The Commute is a power fantasy game about street harassment. Built around true-to-life experiences of catcalling, the game highlights the destructive nature of street harassment while inviting players to choose how to “deal with it.”
You play as Amber, who just wants to wear her clothes of choice and get to the metro with her emotional health intact. Help her dodge catcallers and their harmful words, and fight back when things get out of hand.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Her Parlour</title>
      <link>http://lishanaz.com/lishanaz/public/her-parlour/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://lishanaz.com/lishanaz/public/her-parlour/</guid>
      <description>Her Parlour is a new style of museum audio tour that challenges visitors to find art pieces as they progress through a story. Designed for the Home Décor exhibit of The Getty, Her Parlour transforms the exhibit into the estate of Adrienne, a middle-aged wife in 18th century France who is trying to fix her failing marriage. Convinced she can rekindle the love of her husband by reminding him of their newlywed days, she searches for the artifacts that will bring back his first memories of her.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beauty of H Street</title>
      <link>http://lishanaz.com/lishanaz/public/beauty-of-h-street/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://lishanaz.com/lishanaz/public/beauty-of-h-street/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Beauty of H Street&amp;rdquo; examines the history of H Street Northeast, once a hub of African American barber shops and salons. The documentary follows the neighborhood from the ‘60s riots to destitution to its current state as one of the fastest gentrifying neighborhoods in Washington, DC. It features interviews from barbershop owners who were there from the &amp;rsquo;60s until now, and spoken word from DC youth.
We won a grant from The Humanities Council to complete this project.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eugene&#39;s Cove</title>
      <link>http://lishanaz.com/lishanaz/public/eugenes-cove/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 00:15:59 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://lishanaz.com/lishanaz/public/eugenes-cove/</guid>
      <description>In 1919, at a segregated beach on the south side of Chicago, 17-year-old Eugene Williams was stoned to death after floating across the color line in Lake Michigan. His drowned body echoes the millions of Black bodies thrown overboard during the middle passage–a reminder that our relationship with water continues to be shaped by racial violence and greed.
Building on the legend of an underwater paradise prevalent throughout the African diaspora, Eugene&amp;rsquo;s Cove by Lishan AZ imagines an underwater world where victims of racial and colonial violence sank and became something more.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Staring at the Dark</title>
      <link>http://lishanaz.com/lishanaz/public/staring-at-the-dark/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2022 00:15:59 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://lishanaz.com/lishanaz/public/staring-at-the-dark/</guid>
      <description>“They seemed to be staring at the dark, but their eyes were watching God.”
–Zora Neale Hurston, Their Eyes Were Watching God
Solo Exhibition at Antenna Gallery in New Orleans, LA On View: July 9 - August 7, 2022 </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tracking Ida</title>
      <link>http://lishanaz.com/lishanaz/public/tracking-ida/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://lishanaz.com/lishanaz/public/tracking-ida/</guid>
      <description>Tracking Ida is an educational alternate reality game (ARG) inspired by the pioneering investigative journalism of Ida B. Wells in the 1890s. Players uncover Ida B. Wells’ crusade against lynching and use her strategies to investigate police and vigilante killings today. Along the way, they solve puzzles, decode messages through a phonograph, role-play as investigative journalists, and interview members of their community.
Awards:
2017 Best Gameplay at Games for Change in New York, NY 2017 Impact Award at the Independent Games Festival (Indicade) in Los Angeles, CA Selected Festivals and Exhibits: 2019 SAAM Arcade @ Smithsonian American Art Museum in Washington, DC 2017 Finalist Exhibit @ Independent Games Festival (Indiecade) in Los Angeles, CA 2019 Arcade @ Museums and the Web (MuseWeb) in Boston, MA 2017 Finalist Exhibit @ Games for Change in New York, NY 2017 Group Exhibition @ Tokyo University of the Arts Museum in Tokyo Japan 2017 Electronic Entertainmetn Expo (E3) in Los Angeles, CA Collaborators:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://lishanaz.com/lishanaz/public/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://lishanaz.com/lishanaz/public/about/</guid>
      <description>Lishan AZ is a multi-disciplinary artist working in immersive installation, interactive media, photography and film. She explores themes of home, intimacy, and interiority. Her work revives lost narratives in order to contextualize contemporary issues and discover/recover possibilities for our present condition.
Lishan holds an MFA in interactive media and games from the University of Southern California. Her game Tracking Ida was awarded Best Gameplay at Games for Change and the Impact Award at the International Festival of Independent Games (Indiecade).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://lishanaz.com/lishanaz/public/archivedprojects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://lishanaz.com/lishanaz/public/archivedprojects/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://lishanaz.com/lishanaz/public/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://lishanaz.com/lishanaz/public/contact/</guid>
      <description>Email: lishan@lishanaz.com</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
