<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Lishan AZ</title>
    <link>https://lishanaz.com/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Lishan AZ</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 00:15:59 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://lishanaz.com/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Eugene&#39;s Cove</title>
      <link>https://lishanaz.com/eugenes-cove/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 00:15:59 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lishanaz.com/eugenes-cove/</guid>
      <description>In 1919, at a segregated beach on the south side of Chicago, 17-year-old Eugene Williams was stoned to death after floating across the color line in Lake Michigan. His drowned body echoes the millions of Black bodies thrown overboard during the middle passage–a reminder that our relationship with water continues to be shaped by racial violence and greed.
Building on the legend of an underwater paradise prevalent throughout the African diaspora, Eugene&amp;rsquo;s Cove by Lishan AZ imagines an underwater world where victims of racial and colonial violence sank and became something more.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Staring at the Dark</title>
      <link>https://lishanaz.com/staring-at-the-dark/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2022 00:15:59 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lishanaz.com/staring-at-the-dark/</guid>
      <description>“They seemed to be staring at the dark, but their eyes were watching God.”
–Zora Neale Hurston, Their Eyes Were Watching God
Solo Exhibition at Antenna Gallery in New Orleans, LA On View: July 9 - August 7, 2022 </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tracking Ida</title>
      <link>https://lishanaz.com/tracking-ida/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lishanaz.com/tracking-ida/</guid>
      <description>Tracking Ida is an educational alternate reality game (ARG) inspired by the pioneering investigative journalism of Ida B. Wells in the 1890s. Players uncover Ida B. Wells’ crusade against lynching and use her strategies to investigate police and vigilante killings today. Along the way, they solve puzzles, decode messages through a phonograph, role-play as investigative journalists, and interview members of their community.
Awards:
2017 Best Gameplay at Games for Change in New York, NY 2017 Impact Award at the Independent Games Festival (Indicade) in Los Angeles, CA Selected Festivals and Exhibits: 2019 SAAM Arcade @ Smithsonian American Art Museum in Washington, DC 2017 Finalist Exhibit @ Independent Games Festival (Indiecade) in Los Angeles, CA 2019 Arcade @ Museums and the Web in Boston, MA 2017 Finalist Exhibit @ Games for Change in New York, NY 2017 Group Exhibition @ Tokyo University of the Arts Museum in Tokyo Japan 2017 Electronic Entertainmetn Expo (E3) in Los Angeles, CA Collaborators:</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
